People do not want information, they
want a feeling. There is no such thing
as too long, there is only too boring.
You need A+ content with C- delivery.
The rule of 100. 100 videos every time,
choose one thing to do better. If you've
ever thought about building an audience
or building a brand online, this video
is for you because I've done it.
In the last 5 years, I've built a
podcast. This podcast has done over 100
million downloads. We've got a million
YouTube subscribers, half a million on
Twitter. I've got some experience at
building audiences and I've learned what
I would call a pretty um
non-conventional playbook. So, this is
my non-obvious advice for you because
you've heard all the obvious advice. The
obvious advice is you should post
consistently and you should do XYZ. This
is not that. Okay, so here's the advice
that if I was sitting down younger me
who was interested in doing this,
actually wanted to be a content creator,
wanted to have an audience, um these are
the kind of the hard lessons learned.
Non-obvious advice number one, who
follows you is what's important, not how
many people follow you.
Um I heard Tim Ferriss say this once. He
said uh would you rather have 100,000
people on Earth at random read your book
or, you know, the 100 CEOs of the
Fortune 100? That 100 is worth more than
100,000. And so, you really want to get
intentional about who is the audience
that you really really care about. If
you're making sports content for
athletes, then you really want to figure
out who's that type of person and how do
I make sure that my content will
resonate with them. I'm okay getting
less views. I'm okay getting less likes
as long as it's the right people and the
right likes, that my message is finding
the right ears. You know, just to give
you a like a business analogy.
There's a car analogy, which is
dangerous because I'm like the only guy
on Earth that doesn't care about cars.
Uh but General Motors will sell, I don't
know, 2.5 million cars a year. The
company is worth $50 billion. Ferrari
sells 13,000. So, 2.6 million versus
13,000, but Ferrari is worth $80
million. It can sell 200 times fewer
customers than GM, but still be more
valuable because it's getting luxury
customers, high-end customers. And I
think if you are like me, you're
creating, ideally, like sort of upmarket
content. You're creating content that um
you know, is a little bit more
intelligent, not the sort of like mass
market stuff, unless that's really the
game you want to play. Hey, real quick,
if you listen to this episode and you
like what you're hearing, don't worry,
you don't have to take any notes. The uh
sponsor of today's episode, HubSpot, has
put together everything in this episode
as a free guide for you to download. All
the notes, everything I'm talking about
here in a nice clean little note
structure for you. It's in the link in
the description below.
All right, number two.
Most people don't know what they should
talk about. And I have some advice here,
which is very simple. I got this from my
trainer. He said, "Look, the best
products in the world are ones where the
founder just pushes a little bit of
themselves out into the world. It's
like, you know, going inside out. Just
whatever's in your belly, how do you
push it out? I call this finding your
inner nerd. The question you should ask
yourself is not kind of like, what does
the audience want? But what is the thing
you nerd out about the most? Maybe it's
something that sounds a little boring,
or you like it to a degree that's sort
of abnormal. That weird is something you
want to lean into, not lean away from.
So, uh it might look odd to others, but
it feels right to you. For example, I
remember uh going to my uncle's house
one time, and he took me to the
basement. No, don't worry, it's not that
type of story. He He down in the
basement, he's got a model train set up.
And every night, he was spending hours
tinkering with this model train set. It
was so elaborate. And he flicked it on
to show me, and he showed me that the
lights The timing of the green lights
and the yellow lights were like were
like realistic. So, he's showing me like
his proudest work, and I'm thinking,
"Wow, my uncle's the biggest dork." But
for content, that's actually what you
want, because it turns out the internet
is this amazing thing where you will
find the other thousand, 10,000,
100,000, or million people who are just
as nerdy about the same topics as you.
This is why you'll see creators who go
viral about random stuff. We talked on
this podcast before about the woman
who's doing perfume tours in New York.
She's just nerding her inner nerd is
about scent, and she knows more about
scent than you know about scent. She
cares more than you care, but she will
find the audience of people who care as
much about perfume and scents as she
does. There's a guy who does workwear,
like men's style, and he just loves
writing about the the pant cuffs and the
hems and the cuts, and he'll write a
thousand words on this stuff, something
I would never do. But one, it eliminates
competition because while there's many
people creating content, very few people
will have the same taste palette, the
same inner nerd as you. So you end up in
this If you just follow that, you're
just honest about it, you will end up
almost with no competition, which sounds
crazy. It's like being in an incredibly
crowded room, yet you have five feet of
space all around you. And the second is
that
success is a guarantee.
Because if your If your version of
success is, "Am I famous with millions
of followers yet?" you're going to be
unhappy for a long time, probably
forever. But if you really just focus
on, "Dude, how do I just talk about the
stuff that I love, the stuff that I find
really fun?" then every day is a win,
and you will attract, brick by brick,
the right audience for you. You shift
your odds of success from less than 1%
to 100% cuz you're going to be playing a
different game. You know, the game
you'll be playing is where playing is
winning versus only if I'm successful,
then it's a win. Learn the five D's. Uh
so most people just want to be famous,
but I recommend having a different goal.
The goal is not to be well known, it is
to be known well. What does that mean?
What does it mean for somebody to know
you well?
Well, you want to be able to share your
stories, your hopes, your dreams, your
fears, your obsessions. I call these the
five D's. So the first D is done. What
have I done? What is my track record?
Your audience should know that about
you. What have you done in life?
Deliver. What do you deliver for people
who follow you? What's the service you
offer? What's the value add you give
them? Why should somebody follow you?
Do. What do you do for work? What do
What do for fun? What do you like to do?
People should know about your work, your
hobbies, those sorts of things.
Dreams. What are you shooting for?
What's the dream? For example, if you
follow Gary V, you might know that Gary
V's dream is to buy the Jets one day.
And he tells people this very openly,
and it's a way it's a point of
attachment. It's something people can
remember about you, something they can
know about you, something they can
relate to. So, you got to know what you
do, what you deliver,
um what you've done, what you dream
about, and lastly, dork out about. What
are you What are you really into? What
do you collect? Cuz that's the stuff
people are going to send you. And it's
amazing when you wake up and your inbox
is full of almost like people all around
the world hunting down the things that
you will find awesome because they
understand you and they know you well.
And every day you're going to be
receiving little gifts, little nuggets
from people. Not just people saying,
"Hey, I love your content." But, "Hey,
man, you You Have you seen this? You're
going to love this." That's what happens
with me with this podcast. People know I
nerd out about I dork out about
in niche internet businesses, businesses
that are really, you know, off the
radar, you know, people who
uh live life a certain way, highly
intentional ways they live life. And so,
that's what they send me. Everywhere I
wake Every day I wake up, it's like
Christmas Day. I got gifts to unwrap
about that stuff. If you do the five
D's, you know, two things will happen.
One, the audience feels more connection
with you. So, the key is connection.
They don't want You don't just want them
to know your name and your face. You
want them to actually know your story,
know what you're all about, know what
you're into, know your dreams, all that
stuff.
And the second is that you get luckier.
Uh you know, when when people know you
really well, they're going to send you
the right types of deals, the right
types of recommendations, the right
types of products. Lesson number four.
Part of me is thinking right now as I'm
recording this video, man, this is
getting kind of long. Should I keep this
shorter? But, you're still here. There's
a rule in content, which is that there's
no such thing as too long, only too
boring.
If you want proof, go look at the number
one podcaster in the world, Joe Rogan.
His average episodes are 3 hours long.
And he said when he started that all of
his friends told him, like, "Dude,
that's ridiculous. You need to have like
a 22-minute podcast, a 44-minute
podcast, the average length of the the
daily American's commute." And he just
said, "No, I want to have the types of
conversations I I like having long
conversations with people. I like
hanging out with people for a while.
That's when I feel like I really get to
know them."
And it works because there is no such
thing as too long, there is only too
boring. And if you ever feel like
something's too long, you just have to
reframe it in your mind as, "Maybe it's
too boring." And try to make it more
interesting instead. All right, number
five. Don't worry about your writing
style or your production quality up
front. What you want to do when you
start with content is avoid the trap of
thinking you need a fancy camera and a
fancy set and it needs to be written
well. No, no, no. You need A+ content
with C- delivery. That is a great
starting point. Because what people try
to do instead is they try to have A+
delivery with C- content and that's a
death trap. You are going to waste hours
on your packaging, on your
post-production,
instead of just trying to find the most
interesting stuff you can and have
interesting [clears throat] things to
say.
If you want evidence, go look at some of
the most famous podcasters you see
today. Go look at Chris Williamson's
old, you know, videos. They're all there
online. You can go see them. Go look at
Mr. Beast's channel. Go scroll Just
click Just go on YouTube and click
oldest. You'll see him in his bedroom in
a white t-shirt with no production
value, literally counting to 100,000.
He's doing something interesting, but he
doesn't look that interesting. Go look
at Joe Rogan's original episode. It's
like It's It's crazy. It's like After
Effects snowflakes falling on his head.
It's like cheesy as all hell. He's using
an old ugly webcam.
And he, you know, he became the king of
podcast. And the reason that works is
because you focus on content first,
packaging later. Number six. All right,
we're getting to the end here. Create a
binge bank. At the beginning, when you
try to create content, your numbers are
going to be small, which will lead you
to have doubts, which will lead you to
thinking to yourself, "Man, should I
even be doing this? It's kind of
embarrassing. What's the point of even
doing this?" Well, here's the trick. At
the beginning, instead of focusing on
the fact that eight people viewed your
content, tell yourself you're building
an asset. You're building a binge bank.
A binge bank is sort of like your
personal Netflix-like binge-worthy show.
It's like an hour of content that if
somebody consumed, they would love you.
And you just need to have an amazing
hour. Whether that's, you know, six or
seven blog posts, whether that's, you
know, six or seven videos or podcast
episodes. You just want to create that
seven, eight, that first season of
content that, sure, nobody's watching
today, but if they ever did binge it and
they went an hour straight of your
content, they would walk away being
like, "Wow, who is this guy? Who is this
girl? I love them. This They're This
person's amazing. Why aren't more people
talking about this?" That is your goal
at the beginning. You don't focus on the
number, you focus on creating that power
hour of content. Lesson number seven,
people do not want information, they
want a feeling.
I was wrong about this for a long time.
I thought that I needed to have the most
interesting, intelligent information in
the world. And I really focused on
content as this sort of transfer of
information. But the truth is that if
you ask people, even people who are fan
of you, "Hey, you know, people come up
to you all the time. I'm I'm out with my
family, they'll say, "Oh, man, hey, I
love the channel, love the show, love
the podcast. Oh, it's so amazing." And
I'll say,
"Awesome. What What's something that
you've taken away from it? Right? What's
your favorite episode? What What's
something you learned recently from it?"
People really struggle to do that. And
it's not a knock on them, it's just the
way that people consume content, which
is that a lot of content is going to go
in one ear and out the other. But
something happens in between it coming
in and it coming out, which is that a
person has a feeling. And so, the advice
I got on this, which turned out to be
very true,
was to think of your channel, your blog,
your website, your book, whatever it is,
as a little shop in the world's most
crowded flea market. And you're not
selling stuff, you're selling a feeling.
So, for example, David Blaine sells the
feeling of awe. When you see him do
something that just blows your mind,
it's awe-inspiring.
He just It doesn't matter whether he's
swallowing a frog or he's, you know,
suspended in an ice cube for 18 hours or
he's levitating on the street, he is
trying to sell the feeling of awe. He
finds a million different ways to give
you that feeling. James Clear, the
author of Atomic Habits, sells the
feeling of self-control. A feeling that
you could take control of your life. And
all of his advice, no matter what the
blog is about, will give you that
underlying feeling of control. Dana
White has said this. He goes, at his
press conference he said, "We sell holy
moments live on pay-per-view." You
know, holy that's the feeling that
they sell. Every fight is just designed
to create a holy moment. Tony
Robbins sells a feeling of motivation
and CrossFit sells you like a a
satisfying sweat at the end of every
workout. Is CrossFit actually the best
workout? No, but they're amazing at
delivering a satisfying sweat and that
gets people addicted. And if you give
people a feeling once or twice, you
might get a follow. But if you can give
people that feeling every day, you'll
get a lifelong fan. And so, find out the
feeling you want to sell and then figure
out how to deliver that consistently,
more reliably than they can get anywhere
else, and they'll keep coming back to
your shop. Lesson number eight,
be so good they can't ignore you. So,
I've become friends with Mr. Beast over
the last few years and I love his
attitude towards winning. When people
ask him for advice on how to be a
successful YouTuber, which he gets all
the time, he just tells them one very
simple thing. Make 100 videos.
And every video, pick one thing to do
better. The rule of a hundred, hundred
videos every time choose one thing to
get better. It could be the the
thumbnail, the hook, the storytelling,
the the color editing, it doesn't matter
what it is. Pick one thing every time
and do it and come back and talk to me
over after you're done that a hundred
times. This is amazing advice on two
levels because number one, it just
shooes people away because most people
are not serious and so you gave them a
you gave unserious people a serious task
that'll just keep them busy. They they
won't ever come back cuz they won't do
it. And the people who do do it, by the
hundredth video, they never need to come
back. They don't need his advice.
They're too busy with their success.
And so, this rule of a hundred is is the
real algorithm that you should follow.
Forget the the news feed. The algorithm
is
a hundred pieces of content each time
pick one and do it well. If you do that,
you will become so good
that they can't ignore you. And so,
that's my unconventional advice for
anybody who wants to be a creator. Let's
review. So, the first thing you will do
is you will stop worrying about the
numbers. You will think about who you
want to follow you more than how many
people follow you and you'll try to make
content working backwards. Imagine they
were sitting in that chair in front of
you.
Could you with a straight face tell them
this? Would they get excited or would
they be like,
you know, this is kind of whack? So,
focus on who, not how many. Number two,
unleash your inner nerd. It is what
differentiates you and it creates a
world where somehow there's a billion
people creating content and you will
have no competition because nobody can
match your taste palette, the things you
nerd out about, and the way you nerd out
about them more than anybody else.
Number three, you want to remember the
five D's. So, when you create content,
write these. What have I done? What do I
deliver? What do I do? What do I dream
about? What do I dork out about? And
create That creates your content list.
You want to create storylines underneath
each one of those. If you just sit for
10 minutes and you just brainstorm ideas
under each one of those D's, you'll have
like a year of content, a pipeline that
you can then attack. Number four,
there's no such thing as too long,
there's only too boring. Content should
be as long as it is interesting. That's
the rule.
Number five, don't worry about
packaging. You want A+ content with C-
packaging, not C- content with A+
packaging. Go look at all your favorite
creators, go sort by oldest, go read
their old stuff, it's terrible. The
packaging is always terrible, but the
interestingness was always there. They
always had find heat first before they
find polish.
Number six, the trick at the beginning,
when your numbers are low, is to focus
on not the numbers, but creating a binge
bank. You create your one hour of
material, like a Netflix show. If
somebody binged you, they would walk
away saying, "I love this person. This
This person is amazing. I can't believe
they don't have a big following. I'm so
lucky to be here first."
Uh number seven, make sure you remember
that you at the end of the day you
deliver a feeling to people, not
information. Find out what that feeling
is. David Blaine's That feeling is awe.
James Clear's is self-control. The UFC's
is holy moments. You know,
CrossFit's is a satisfying sweat. Figure
out the feeling you want to deliver and
then deliver that more consistently than
anyone else. That is your winning
strategy. And lastly, the rule of 100
from Mr. Beast.
If you're going to make content, focus
on making 100 of them before you judge
yourself. And each time, just try to
make one thing better. And if you do the
real work, you would come You will
become so good they can't ignore you. If
you look at what people hate about
creators now, it is definitely like a
processed foods type of thing. It's like
a There's something artificial about the
whole thing. People People You know, it
lost some of the charm of the early days
when people were just vlogging their
life or people would sort of stumble
into an audience. They didn't start for
that reason. They were just sharing
their work online or expressing
themselves or putting their art out
there and like they would get a
following. And now people know there's
big rewards for doing it. And so it
attracted kind of the wrong type of
person or the wrong mentality. And I
think in a world of AI
where any you know, literally the
computer's going to be making content
that's hyper addictive and hyper
entertaining
what's going to be left is going to be
when you bump into a person that feels
real.
And we all have very good
detectors. We can actually sense when
somebody's real and it stands out and
it's very different. And so I just think
that's going to be the place where you
know, the water's not going to drown
you. If you actually operate that way,
that'll be what sustains in the future
and and I think is what people crave
more than ever now. You see this like
Sam Sulek. He's bodybuilding bodybuilder
guy. You kind of get to go on a workout
with him. He talks while he's doing it.
It's pretty live. He doesn't feel like
he's performing for you. He feels like
he's letting you in.
And that it's surprising to people why
that was so successful, but it to me
it's not very surprising because I think
if you notice a lot of what I said
boils back down to like just be
yourself. But the problem is if you tell
somebody just be yourself or be
authentic, these are hollow words. And
so what I wanted to give people was the
actual playbook of how you actually be
yourself. At the end of the day, you do
all that stuff, I guarantee you you will
have as big of an audience as you
desire. And maybe you'll find that being
famous wasn't all it's cracked up to be,
but that's another message for another
day. For now, take this, use this well,
go forth and prosper.